This movie is so real it makes every other movie in this town look like a movie.
The Laughing Policeman is a crime, thriller film directed by Stuart Rosenberg.
When a gunman opens fire on a crowded city bus in San Francisco, Detective Dave Evans is
killed, along with the man he'd been following in relation to a murder.
Evans' partner, Sgt.
Jake Martin, becomes obsessed with solving the case.
Sgt. Jake Martin SFPD, played by Walter Matthau.
Insp. Leo Larsen SFPD, played by Bruce Dern.
Insp. James Larrimore SFPD, played by Louis Gossett Jr..
Henry Camerero, played by Albert Paulsen.
Lt. Nat Steiner SFPD, played by Anthony Zerbe.
Insp. John Pappas SFPD, played by Val Avery.
The Laughing Policeman (released in the UK as An Investigation of Murder) is a 1973 American neo-noir
thriller film loosely based on the 1968 novel of the same name by Maj Sjöwall and Per Wahlöö.
The setting of the story is transplanted from Stockholm to San Francisco.
It is directed by Stuart Rosenberg and features
Walter Matthau as Detective Jake Martin.
The film explores themes of san francisco,
california, mass murder, murder, killer.
The tone is intense.